nirvanashop.com 2019-03-27

# Privacy – Nirvana Shop

## 1What do we do with your information?

  1. When you create an account on this website or buy something in our store as part of the purchase and sales process, we collect the personal information that you provide to us, such as your name, address and e-mail address. The purpose of this is to be able to send you your order and transactional e-mails.
  2. When you search our website, we automatically receive the Internet Protocol address (IP address) of your computer as well as information about your browser and operating system. The purpose of this is to be able to show the website optimally.
  3. E-mail marketing: with your permission we can send you e-mails about our store, new products and other updates.
  4. OpenStreetmap: When you choose to validate your address details with OpenStreetmap, your address details will be send to their website for validation. OpenStreetmap uses your data to check if that is correct. The address details that we send is not saved on their side.
  5. Track & Trace: If your order is shipped with Track & Trace, your address and e-mail address will be shared with the post-processing company.
  6. If your payment is arranged with a direct payment method such as credit card, your name, address, e-mail address and necessary details - like the credit card number - can be sent to the payment service provider.

## 2Permission

  1. When we share your data with third parties such as the post-processing company or Payment Service Provider, we will request your permission at the time by means of the check box. If you do not want to give permission, you can not use the service in question.
  2. If you want to receive our newsletter or promotional e-mails, we will only do so if you have given us permission to do so. You can withdraw that permission yourself at any time.
  3.  **How do I withdraw my consent?**
  4. Promotional e-mail/newsletter: If you change your mind after your opt-in, you can withdraw your consent by logging in to your account and de-select the e-mail option. In addition, we display a unsubscribe link on every promotional e-mail/newsletter that you can use to withdraw your consent.
  5. Track & Trace: If you have given permission to send your order with Track & Trace, you can withdraw this permission as long as your order has not yet been sent. You can do this by creating a ticket on our [support website](https://support.nirvanashop.com/) or by sending a message to the address below.
  6. You can withdraw your consent in writing by sending an email to the following address:

privacyofficer @ nirvanashop.com

  7. You can also send a written request instead to:
    1.   
Nirvana Shop  
c.o. Privacy Compliance Officer  
Munterslaan 4a  
2014 KW Haarlem  
The Netherlands

## 3Disclosure

  1. We will share your personal information with legal authorities if we have the legal obligation or if you breach the service conditions.
  2. In addition, there is a legal obligation to inform you about the personal data that we process from you if you so request. If you want to know which personal data we process from you, you can request this at the address below. We will send you your details within 1 month. If we are unable to realize this within the set period of 1 month, you will receive notification within 1 month.
  3. You must be able to identify yourself with your legal identity document such as a passport or ID issued by your government.
  4.     1.   
Nirvana Shop  
c.o. Privacy Compliance Officer  
Munterslaan 4a  
2014 KW Haarlem  
The Netherlands

privacyofficer @ nirvanashop.com

## 4Removing personal data

  1. Orders that have never been paid for are set to canceled after 3 months and removed from our database after six months.
  2. In connection with the Tax Code, we are obliged to keep order data for 7 years. That includes personal data. For this reason, we remove personal data from accounts with paid orders that are no longer active for more than 7 years.
  3. For customers that did not place any order we remove the account plus all related data from our database 2 years after sign-up.
  4. You can submit a request at any time to delete your personal data. If we have the legal obligation to do so, certain information will have to be retained according to the legal deadline. In that case, that data will not be deleted.
  5. Your data will be deleted within 1 month after we receive your request. If we are unable to realize this within the set period of 1 month, you will be notified of this within 1 month of the request.
  6. If you want your data to be deleted, you can submit a request to the address below. You must be able to identify yourself with a valid identity card such as a passport or an ID issued by your government.
  7.     1.   
Nirvana Shop  
c.o. Privacy Compliance Officer  
Munterslaan 4a  
2014 KW Haarlem  
The Netherlands

privacyofficer @ nirvanashop.com

## 5Services of third parties

  1. In general, the third-party suppliers we use will only collect, use and disclose your information to the extent necessary to enable them to provide the services they provide to us.
  2. With external suppliers with whom we share your personal data, we have, according to the legal obligation, a processor's agreement that regulates how your personal data are handled.
  3. As soon as you leave the website of our store or are redirected to a website or application of a third party, this privacy statement is no longer applicable. Instead, the privacy statement of that third party applies.
  4.  **Links**
  5. When you click on links in our store, they can lead you away from our site. We are not responsible for the privacy rules of other sites and encourage you to read their privacy statement.

## 6Security

  1. To protect your personal information, we take reasonable precautions and follow the best practices in the industry to ensure that it is not misappropriated, misused, accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed.  
Passwords are stored encrypted using one-way encryption.
  2. If you provide your credit card information to us, the information is encrypted using secure socket layer (SSL) technology. We follow all PCI-DSS requirements and implement additional generally accepted industry standards.

## 7Age

  1. The law requires that persons under the age of 16 require permission from their legal representative when using Internet services. When in doubt about the age of a customer, we reserve the right to ask for identification.

## 8Changes to this policy

  1. We reserve the right to change this privacy policy at any time, so view it regularly. Changes and clarifications are immediately effective after being placed on the website. If we make substantial changes to this policy, we will report this when accessing the website.
  2. If our store is bought or merged with another company, your information can be transferred to the new owners so that we can continue to sell products to you.

## 9Questions and contact details

  1. If you wish to access, correct, change or delete personal information that we have about you, wish to file a complaint or simply request more information, please contact our Privacy Compliance Officer:
    1.   
Nirvana Shop  
c.o. Privacy Compliance Officer  
Munterslaan 4a  
2014 KW Haarlem  
The Netherlands

privacyofficer @ nirvanashop.com
